

Taha Heidari

Nationality: Iranian

Date of Birth: 20.09.1996

Gender: Male

Contact

Address

Otakaari, 20, A2, Espoo, Finland, 02150

Email:

Newsince2@gmail.com

Phone:

(+358)468964613

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahaheidari-0294261a5

Hobbies

Kiteboarding Running Guitar Playing

About ME

Master's Student in Automation Engineering with about 2 years of work experience in Data Engineering and 1 year of academic work as a Teaching Assistant in Machine Learning Courses at university.

Working with different datasets and implementing different Machine Learning methods. Extracting Bayesian Inference from datasets using Monte Carlo Markov Chain (MCMC) methods. Working with Flutter as a powerful framework to build user-friendly apps.

Eager to learn new frameworks in Machine Learning, Data Science and Al. currently looking forward to get a master's thesis position.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Aalto University

Master of Science in Automation and Electrical Engineering 01/09/2021 – CURRENT [Espoo, Finland] (GPA: 4.13/5)

- O Major Specialization: Control, Robotics and Autonomous Systems
- O Minor Specialization: Machine Learning, Data Science and Artificial Intelligence (minor courses)
 - Machine Learning (5/5)
 - Machine Learning with Python (5/5)
 - Deep Learning (5/5)
 - Artificial Intelligence (4/5)
 - Deep Learning with Python
 - Machine Learning: Advanced Probabilistic Methods
 - Bayesian Data Analysis
 - Reinforcement Learning
 - Computer Vision
 - Machine Learning: Supervised Methods

Kermanshah University of Technology Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering 23/09/2007 – 19/02/2012 [Tehran, Iran] (GPA: 4.59/5)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer

Peyman Gharb Company

01.08.2019 - 31.08.2021 [Kermanshah, Iran]

- Data Analyzing: predicting the best time to exit 20 KV feeders from the network based on the demand and generated electricity from power plants
- MCMC analysis of supply-and-demand using different Bayesian deep learning architectures (analyzing the peak hours of electricity consumption to decide which power units must be cut from the network)

ML Teaching Assistant

Sharif University of Technology

01.01.2022 – Current – Tehran, Iran

- Designing different Machine Learning assignments for master's students
- Instructing students in their programming assignments during the exercise sessions
- Programming the ID3 decision tree of the IRIS dataset on adult's income level and modifying it by pruning algorithms without using Python ML libraries
- Programming the Bayes method of a plant-classifier on the IRIS dataset on flowers without using Python ML libraries
- Programming the Logistic Regression algorithm on a text classifier with Reuters-21578 dataset and comparing it with a Naïve Bayes classifier with the same dataset in terms of accuracy and speed, training the algorithm with k-fold cross validation, analyzing the effects of overfitting of training data on the results
- Linear and nonlinear programming of SVM algorithm in different moods like soft, RBF kernel, and polynomial kernel for classifying the IRIS dataset on adult's income level
- Classifying the MNIST dataset with a multilayer perceptron neural network (MLP)

MCMC Analysis Project Work

Aalto University

11.01.2022 - 03.06.2022 - Espoo, Finland

- Developing several Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) algorithms from scratch to predict the future population of Canadian lynxes as our famous time-series dataset
- Applying MCMC methods to Deep Learning Architectures for Bayesian ML Analysis

Honors

- 1st Rank in 2-stage Regional Physics Competitions, Kermanshah, Iran (2012).
- 1st Rank, Achieving the highest GPA among all 40 university Electrical Power Engineering graduate students with GPA: 4.59/5, Kermanshah University of Technology, Iran (2014-2018).
- 4th Rank, 22nd National Collegiate Scientific Olympiad in Electrical Engineering, First Stage, Kermanshah, Iran (2017).
- 3rd Rank, 23rd National Collegiate Scientific Olympiad in Electrical Engineering, First Stage, Kermanshah, Iran (2018).
- 31st Rank, 22nd National Collegiate Scientific Olympiad in Electrical Engineering, Second Stage, Tehran, Iran (2017).
- 29th Rank, 23rd National Collegiate Scientific Olympiad in Electrical Engineering, Second Stage, Tehran, Iran (2018).

Language Skills

MOTHER TONGUE(S):

Persian

OTHER LANGUAGE(S):

English

Listening Speaking Reading Writing C1 C1 C1 C1

Finnish

Listening Speaking Reading Writing A1 A1 A1 A1

Other Skills

Programming Languages

R, Python, JavaScript, Dart, C, C++, Java, MATLAB

Machine Learning

TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, scikit-learn, pandas, NumPy

Software & Tools

LaTex, Git, PowerBI

Cloud Services

Microsoft Azure

Databases

MySQL

Web

Django, Flutter

Other skills

Leadership

Time management

Decision-making

Organizational and Excellent Planning skills

Concept Development

Problem solving (problem analysis)

Teamwork

Analytical skills

Creativity